In this video, we'll provide an overview of selling button or coin batteries as individual
ASINs and selling items that contain button or coin batteries.
When listing button or coin batteries or products that contain them in the Amazon U.
S.
store,
sellers must comply with the mandatory U.
S.
Reese's Law 16 CFR 1263 safety standards.
Supplying products that do not comply to consumers in U.
S.
is illegal.
These safety standards became effective in the U.
S.
in 2024 to help reduce the risk of
death and injury associated with the use of button and coin batteries.
Button batteries pose a severe injury risk if ingested.
Button and coin batteries are typically single cell batteries with a diameter greater than
their height.
They are often found in remote controls, watches, and toys.
Customers purchase these batteries as standalone products for items they already own and products
that contain these batteries to help the product operate.
Before listing button or coin batteries for sale on Amazon, you need to apply to sell them.
This is also true for selling an item that contains a button or coin battery, whether
the batteries are intended to be replaced by the consumer, are included with the product
or are sold separately, so it is important to know if any products you plan to list
contain them.
For a battery sold as an individual ASIN or for an item sold that contains a button or
coin battery, you'll need to provide documentation from an accredited organization stating that
the product complies with applicable safety standards.
These standards are enforced by the United States Consumer Product Safety Commission
or CPSC.
You can find a list of the specific policies relevant to your product on the Button cell and coin
batteries and products that contain them help page.
You can also find these policies by searching for button batteries in the compliance reference
tool.
Click "View Help Content" to see policy and compliance information.
For each ASIN listed in your email, include documentation for each relevant policy.
Button and coin batteries pose serious risks if they end up in someone's body.
The US has regulations in place to make sure people who purchase button and coin batteries
are aware of these risks and can take steps to prevent them.
You're responsible for ensuring that your products and their packaging contain the proper
warning labels.
All labels should use internationally recognized safety alert symbols and include a standard
alert word like "warning".
Whether you're selling button and coin batteries as individual ASINs or selling products that
contain them, the packaging must be clearly marked with a warning about the risks.
It should also provide guidance to keep the battery out of reach of children and should
advise to immediately seek medical attention should a battery be inside any part of a person's
body.
There are two additional requirements for products that contain button and coin batteries in order
to provide protection to the customer.
One, make sure the product provides an adequate mechanism to secure the battery.
Two, make sure the battery will not inadvertently be released during reasonably foreseeable use
or misuse of the product.
The International Electrotechnical Commission or IEC has a specific coding system for labeling
button and coin batteries.
Follow this system to include the proper alpha numeric code in the title and description
of your listing to make sure customers know what they're purchasing.
Every button or coin battery uses one of four types of chemistry to function.
The first letter of the alpha numeric label refers to whether the battery is alkaline,
silver, zinc air or lithium.
The second character in the label is always R, which stands for round, the shape of a button
or coin battery.
Then there is a set of numbers, first the diameter in millimeters and then the height
in millimeters, including tenths of millimeters if necessary.
For example, a lithium battery that is 20 millimeters in diameter and 3.2 millimeters
in height would be labeled as CR 2032.
You're now prepared to identify ASINs that either are or contain button and coin batteries,
apply to sell them and convey the right safety information to the customer.
Remember to refer to the help page for specific information about applicable regulations and
Amazon's policies.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.